A Guide to the Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection, 1873-1982 (bulk 1903-1956): SC 0050
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 2: Maps, 1903-1982 1903-1956
  - City of Harrisonburg sewage pumping station for South Avenue, 1951 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of W.P. Liskey's Property located at Harrisonburg VA as surveyed and divided into 3 lots, 1951 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of W.P. Liskey's Property Located at Harrisonburg VA. As Surveyed and divided into 3 Lots (W. Water St, Elm St), 1951 (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Proposed set back line Wolfe Street, 1951 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - Telephone Poles, Power Poles, Water Lines Connection, 1951 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - To the City of Harrisonburg Va, Deed Reference, 1951 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Tract of Land to be Conveyed by K.A. Keithly to County Reality and Investment Company (includes attached Deed information), 1951 (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Map of Harrisonburg Va, 1951 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - Airhart Addtion City of Harrisonburg & Rockingham County, 1952 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - City of Harrisonburg, VA Engineering Department Setback Building Lines for Baptist Church Lot, 1952 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of J.M. Kavanaugh's Property Located at Harrisonburg Virginia as Platted From Old Deeds, 1952 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of Proposed Armory Site Located in the southwestern Section of Harrisonburg, 1952 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Rolling Hills Conrad Realty Co., 1952 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Section "A" Rolling Hills Conrad Realty Co., 1952 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Topographic Map for Proposed Armory Site in Harrisonburg, Virginia (Brook Ave, Bruce St, Willow St), 1952 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - Topographic Plan Waterman School Property (Willow St, Gay St), 1952 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - A Plat Showing a parcel of land to be conveyed to the Harrisonburg School Board by the City of Harrisonburg VA copy 1 & 2, 1953 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Layout of Proposed Parking Lot and approaches (Mason Street, Federal Street, Wolfe Street, and Elizabeth Street) copy 1 & 2, 1953 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 4)
  - Plat of Lands to be Sold by Harrisonburg copy 1 & 2, 1953 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing an Easement to the City of Harrisonburg Virginia Over the Land of Francis R. Grattan For the Purpose of Constructing and Maintaining a 20" Cast Iron Sewer Line in the Bed of Blacks Run (West Bruce St), 1953 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Sketch for Fencing Sewage Treatment Plant copy 1 & 2, 1953 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Harrisonburg Virginia Engineering Department: Proposed Changes to Drainage Structure at North Main St. Low Water Bridge, 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of Carrie Rankin's Property proposed to be condemned by city, 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing a Parcel of Land to be conveyed by Annie B. Good to the City of Harrisonburg, VA., 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat showing a survey of the proposed South Ave annexation of part of Rockingham County by the city of Harrisonburg, 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing Land and Building to be purchased by the City of Harrisonburg VA. also showing Land and Building now owned by the City, 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Survey monument marker, 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Westover Hills Addition to Harrisonburg film {Neland Avenue, Toppin Drive), 1954 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - (Item 1) Plat Showing the Extension of South Ave. Thru the lands of Hugh A. Logan, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - (Item 2) Plat showing Western Extension of South Avenue Thru the Lands of Hugh R. Logan (Description of Logan Land in docuements folder), 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Harrisonburg Main Sewer Outfall Easement Revision Across Property of Harrisonburg Livestock Sales, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Harrisonburg Virginia Engineering Department Detail Water Control Gate Riven Rock Intake, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Driveway entrances Carr Bros N. Liberty Street., 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Parcel of Land to be Transferred to the City of Harrisonburg Virginia by Mrs. Bessie B. Knick, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Parking Lot No. 2 Grading Layout, 1955 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Parking lot No. 2 Storm Sewer details, 1955 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Plat of The Sunny Acres Sub-Division Located About One Mile West of Harrisonburg, VA. Belonging to Dold L. Line Weaver, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat of Three lots to be taken from Lands of Mrs. N. Augusta Mauk, Etals Located in Harrisonburg Virginia (Furnance Road), 1955 (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Plat Showing Land Owned by City of Harrisonburg, VA. To Be Conveyed To Greenberk, Inc., 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing Strips of Land to be Acquired by the City of Harrisonburg For the Widening of the Street, 1955 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Plat showing the Extension of South Ave. thru the Lands of Hugh A. Logan with Lots, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing Triangular Shaped Parcel to be Conveyed to the City of Harrisonburg By Ruby H. and Hampton L. Sampson, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat Showing Two Tracts of Land to be Exchanged Between the City of Harrisonburg and L.H. Wenger Located Partly Within and Partly Without the South City Limits of Harrisonburg, 1955 (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Plat Showing Two Tracts of Land to be Exchanged between the City of Harrisonburg and L.H. Wenger. Located partly Within and Partly without the South city Limits of Harrisonburg, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Plat showing Western Extension of South Ave. thru the Lands of Hugh R. Logan, 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - Suggested style of monument for the relocated Ashby memorial (copy 1 & 2), 1955 (Box OV 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Harrisonburg VA Engineering Department: Reenforcing Schedule N. Lib. St. Ret. Wall copy 1 & 2, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - City of Harrisonburg Virginia Engineering Department Survey for Walk Light and Safety Island Intersection of Main Street. and Port Road, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Contour Map of Proposed Park Development by Recreation Department, 1956 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Plat of C.C. Conrad and J.A. Conrad's Property Situated at Harrisonburg Virginia, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat of Land to be Conveyed to City of Harrisonburg by H.G. Preston Located South Rte 710 East of City Limit, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat of Land to be Conveyed to H.G. Preston by City of Harrisonburg Located South Rte. 710 East of City Limit, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat of Shover Farm to be Conveyed to the City of Harrisonburg, VA Central District Rockingham Co. copy 1 & 2 (document Metes and Bound found in folder 13), 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4, Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Plat of Tract to be conveyed to the city of Harrisonburg VA, Located South of Harrisonburg on Route 711 copy 1 & 2, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat Showing Exchange of Land Between City of Harrisonburg and H.G. Preston Located south of Rte 710 at the East Corporate Limit, 1956 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Plat Showing Hugh Logan Sub-division on s. High Street and extension of South Avenue through sub-division, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat Showing Re-Subdivision of Lots in Block 7 of the Airhart Addition Harrisonburg, Virginia (Waterman Street, Hartman Drive), 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Portion of the O.I. Berry Farm to be leased to Harrisonburg, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Preliminery Study for San. Sewer on Harrison Street, 1956 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Sketch showing Strip needed to Widen old Port Road, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Survey Copied from Deed Book 181 Plat Showing Land to be Conveyed to C.C. and J.A. Conrad By J.P. Burke and A.L. Cupp Also Showing Exchange of Land between O.K. and J.A. Conrad and the City of Harrisonburg copy 1 & 2, 1956 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Plat Land Deeded to City of Harrisonburg School Board by City of Harrisonburg Located South of Rte 710 at the East Corporate Limit, 1957 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Newman Estate Located in Harrisonburg, VA. Adjoining Madison College on East Side, 1958 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Profile of Ground & Line Across Berry land Leased by City of Harrisonburg, 1958 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - Plat Showing the Widening and Relocating of Proposed Road Leading to Madison College Through the Lots and Land of Newman and Ewing, Harrisonburg, VA., 1959 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Pleasant Hill Acres E.B. Heatwole and Ruby M. Heatwole, owners Central Dist. Rockingham Co, Virginia, 1959 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Map of Harrisonburg VA and Environs, 1961 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - Route 33, 1961 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Route 42, 1967 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Rockingham Memorial Hospital Site Plan, 1973 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Court Square (copy Showing Spring House and Merchants Pavillion Ideas), 1977 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Plan Court Square, 1977 (Map-case 3, Drawer 6)
  - A Proposal Elizabeth Street Office Building, 1978 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - (Sketch) Harrisonburg Development Concept Plans, 1979 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - Rockingham County VA Base Map by William C Overman and Associates P.C Engineers Surveyors Planners Norfolk VA, 1980 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - City of Harrisonburg vs County of Rockingham Base Map by William C Overman and Associates P.C Engineers Surveyors Planners Norfolk VA and Wiley and Wilson Architects Engineers Planners A professional Corporation, 1981 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - Insert "C" (Proposed annexation line), 1982 (Box OV 2, Folder 4)
  - 8" Pipe line from Spring Steam Plant, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Aero Survey image compiled by photogrammetric methods, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - American Oil Co Lot, Detail of Endwall, Detail of Junction Box, Detail of Junction Box (cont.) four pages, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - American Oil Co. Station off of Main Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - (Baltimore and Ohio railroad, Patterson St., Valley Pike), Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Burke Addition re-subdivision Harrison Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - C Street, "D" Street, Toppin Blvd, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Chart of Municipal Government city of Harrisonburg copy 1 & 2, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Childrens Home Prop. & Ohio avenue extension to main, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - (City, Monticello, Newman to Campbell Street), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - City of Harrisonburg Virginia Typical Section for Revetment Wall, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - City sells to Hatchery, Patterson Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Col. Athletic field driveway, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Col. Athletic Field St. At End of Johnson St., Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Col. Athletic field Washington Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Collins Drain Port Rd., Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Concrete Reservoir, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Corp. Limit drawing, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Detail Form Work for Willow St. Box Culvert, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Drawing of lots, Fairview, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Driveway Reservoir Grade, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - E. Market Furnace Rd. Improvement, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Edge Pavement EBL Market St. Rte 33, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Extension of Franklin Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Finals on Parking Lot (Stapled drawings of roads), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - First floor plan Sunday School rooms People's Church, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Front elevation blueprint People's Church, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Gay Street Bridge Side elevation, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Office Division Budget, portion of a map, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - H.C. Moore lots, Mason Street, Moore 4A, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Insert "A" Harmony Hills Subdivision, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Insert "A", Ordinance line, Alternate line, Prefered line, Triple H farm, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Intake grounds, Dry River, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - J.E. Roller, Paul Site off of Mason Street copy 1 & 2, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - J.H. McGlaughlin, B&O Railroad, Valley Pike copy 1 & 2, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Keister School, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Keister School South Avenue Line, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Keister School South Avenue Line, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Land Exchange between Lincoln and Martz copy 1 & 2, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Liberty St, 3rd St, to North, Undated (Storage 1, Box 2)
  - Little League Baseball Diamond, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Lots owned by A. Peluso (S. High Street), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Lurty Lot, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Map of E.L. Fletcher's Addition to the city of Harrisonburg (Grace St), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City)Map of Gravity Water Supply Harrisonburg Va (Tracing and print Rivenrock to City), Undated (Storage 1, Box 2)
  - Map of L.C. Myers property lying on the East side of South Main St. Harrisonburg Virgina to be conveyed to O.M. Masters by (South Main Street, Bruce Street, Franklin Street, Federal Alley), Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Map of Land Between South Avenue and Maryland Avenue with School Board Property for Keister School, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Map of lots owned by O.M. Masters, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Map of O.M. Master's Property Laying East of South Main Street Harrisonburg Virginia, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Map of residence business and manufacturing sites of Harrisonburg land and improvement Co., Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Map Showing the general location of the Transmission Line Harrisonburg Hydro-Electric Plant, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Maplehurst & Hill Crest Sewer, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - (Mason Street, Bruce to Franklin), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - MD Ave and NY Ave on graph paper, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous drawing of what looks like parcels of land, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. Sibert Land (C.W. Railroad), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Northwest Section St. Layout, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Old City Shop Lot, N Main Street, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Parcel to be conveyed to B.E. Nelson by city of Harrisonburg, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Parking Lot Between Federal Street, Wolf Street and Mason Street, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - People's Church present building and new addition on Monument Ave, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plan Elevation Reienforcing Plans for Reservoir 15 Million Gallons Concrete, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Plan for Widening Main St. South of Bruce St., Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat Harrisonburg Baptist Church Property east side S. Liberty Street. Harrisonburg, VA (for widening), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Plat of Buelah L. Klingstein Property east side S. Liberty Street Harrisonburg, VA, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of George G. Grattan III Property west side S. Liberty Street Harrisonburg, VA, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of Jesse E. and Lulu B. Hair Property west side S. Liberty Street Harrisonburg, VA, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of John R. Gambill Est. Property east side S. Liberty Street Harrisonburg, VA, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of Joseph W. Miller Property west side S. Liberty Street Harrisonburg, VA, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of land donated by A.G. Waterman to the town of Harrisonburg, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of lot laying on the East side of N Main Street, owned by O.M. Masters, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat of the "Spindle" Home Harrisonburg VA (E.Market St), Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Plat of town of Harrisonburg as originally laid out by Harrison's, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Plat Showing Property Owners for Area Bounded by Ott Street, Bruce Street, Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Port Road, Lot 1 Block F, F.O. Funkhouser Lot Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road Lot 2 and Lot 3 Block F, Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Lot. 4 Block F, Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Lot 4 Block I, Mrs. Good Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Lot 8 Block C, Joe Driver Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Lot 9 Block C, W.Z. Mauck Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Lot 10 Block C, Moffett Terrace Geo. T. Wallace III and Dr. Ronald Ney Maplehurst Addition, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Port Road, Crawford Avenue, Hillside Avenue with lots, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Plan Proposed Subdivision Layout of the S.F. Toppin Land Located in Harrisonburg, Virginia, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Profile Highland Ave and Crescent Dr to Long Ave, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Proposed improvements tannery building (temporary plan and permanent plan), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Rear elevation (People's church), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - (Reserved land for Sewage and Electrical Plants)(Layman Pl. 5), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Reservoir Rd. leading from Furnace Road grade, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Right elevation (People's church), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Rivenrock to City Original Survey Drawing Print Tracing, Undated (Storage 1, Box 2)
  - Route 11, Steam Plant, Coal Trestle, B&O RR Houses in this area (R/W to shop written on back), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Schematic Drawing of Topography at Harrisonburg Hydro Plant, Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Sidewalk and Earth Fill Section Willow St. Box Culvert, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Sketch of Proposed Siding Leading From Nail in Tie at the South End of Bridge Across Blacks Run Thence Crossing Run and Over Ralph Monger's Land to Post in the Staples, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - South High Street, Toppin Blvd, "C" Street, "D" Street, Neyland Drive, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - South Main Street lots between C.W. R.R. and Main copy 1 & 2, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Spotswood's Acres subdivision, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Standard Street Signs, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Steps at Ott Street and Campbell Street, Undated (Storage 1, Box 2)
  - Strip Of Land to be Conveyed to the City of Harrisonburg by Chas B. Dallard (Gay Street, Effinger St, Sterling Street, Kelley Street), Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Suggested Location for World War 2 Memorial (Liberty St, Main St, Grace St), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Sunrise and D Street grade, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Sunrise Avenue Profile, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Turbo Generators, Condensers, etc. S. High Street Annexation, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - Valley Street Profile, Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)
  - W. Market St. Storm Drain, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Water Control, City of Harrisonburg Virginia Engineering Dept., Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Water J E Ritchie 10 Inch Water Line (U.S Route 33), Undated (Box OV 3, Folder 2)
  - Water Street Sidewalk and Culvert copy 1,2 & 3, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Wolfe Street Grade between Broad and Myrtle, Undated (Box OV 2, Folder 5)
  - Zirkle Addition (N. Main Street, Johnson Street, Broad Street, Kelly Street), Undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 6, Folder 6)